Jacob M. Davidson

(630) 384-9402 jacobdavidson79@gmail.com jacobmdavidson.com

Summary

A driven .NET developer with experience in a wide range of Microsoft technologies. An enthusiastic high achiever with a passion for continuous learning.

Core Technical Skills

.Net Technologies and Languages: ADO.NET, ASP.NET, C#, Entity Framework, MVC, SignalR, VB.NET, Web Forms, Xamarin

Web Technologies and Languages: AJAX, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, JSON, ¡Query, PHP, XML

Database Management Systems: Oracle, MySQL, SQL Server

Development Tools: Eclipse, SQL Server Management Studio, Team Foundation Server, Visual Studio

Cloud Services: Azure Application Insights, Azure App Service, Azure Content Delivery Network, Azure Service

Bus, Azure SQL Database

Operating Systems: MS Windows, Mac OS X, Linux (Arch, Ubuntu)

Experience

• American Academy of Sleep Medicine

Darien, IL

Programmer 01/2016 – Present

- Provided ongoing maintenance and developed new features for the professional version of the AASM SleepTM telemedicine platform built with ASP.NET Web Forms. This n-tiered application was created using VB.NET, ADO.NET, SignalR, and WebRTC.
 - * Integrated Stripe Connect to allow users to accept client payments.
 - * Created a medical history collection component with a Clinical Document Architecture Release 2 formatted export feature.
 - * Migrated static content to a CDN.
 - * Implemented an Azure Service Bus backplane to facilitate seamless application deployment slot swapping without severing SignalR connections.
- Designed and implemented a lightweight version of the AASM SleepTM telemedicine platform with ASP.NET MVC 5 using C#, Entity Framework 6, SignalR, and WebRTC.
- Developed Android and iOS applications that integrate with the AASM SleepTM telemedicine platform using Xamarin.Android, Xamarin.iOS, SignalR, and WebRTC.
- Provided ongoing maintenance for a console based VB.NET application that uses XSLT transformations to convert XML into HTML for both web-based and Kindle publications.

• Freelance Web Developer

Glen Ellyn, IL

Web developer for various clients.

06/2012 - 06/2014

- Migrated sites from WordPress.org to shared hosting allowing for deeper customization.
- Created custom templates for existing static websites transitioning to a CMS (such as Joomla or WordPress).
- Developed custom WordPress and Joomla plugins.
- Implemented automated backup processes for existing websites.

Education

• University of Illinois at Springfield M.S. Computer Science (GPA: 4.0 out of 4.0)

Springfield, IL 08/2013 – 12/2015

• Purdue University
M.S. Civil Engineering (GPA: 4.0 out of 4.0)

West Lafayette, IN 08/2003 – 12/2004

• Oregon State University
B.S. Civil Engineering (GPA: 3.89 out of 4.0)

Corvallis, OR 09/1998 – 03/2003

Jacob M. Davidson

(630) 384-9402 jacobdavidson79@gmail.com jacobmdavidson.com

Project Highlights

• AASM SleepTM Android App

play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.aasm.sleeptm

08/2017 – Present

Xamarin.Android, C#, SignalR, WebRTC

An Android application that integrates with the AASM SleepTM telemedicine platform allowing patients to engage in telemedicine encounters using an Android device (launched: 09/11/2017).

AASM SleepTM iOS App

itunes.apple.com/us/app/aasm-sleeptm/id1253586517?mt=8

04/2017 - Present

Xamarin.iOS, C#, SignalR, WebRTC

04/2017 - F1eseni

An iOS application that integrates with the AASM SleepTM telemedicine platform allowing patients to engage in telemedicine encounters using an iOS device (launched: 07/31/2017).

• AASM SleepTM Select

sleeptm.com/

ASP.NET 4.5, C#, Entity Framework 6, MS SQL, MVC 5, SignalR, WebRTC

10/2016 – Present

A lightweight version of the AASM SleepTM sleep-specific telemedicine platform that focuses on a simplified telemedicine encounter process (launched 04/20/2017).

• AASM SleepTM Pro

sleeptm.com/

ADO.NET, ASP.NET 4.5, MS SQL, SignalR, VB.NET, Web Forms, WebRTC

1/2016 - Present

A full featured, HIPAA compliant telemedicine platform developed specifically for sleep doctors.

• Elavon Converge Payment Gateway for WooCommerce

jacobmdavidson.com/converge/

PHP, WooCommerce, WordPress

09/2012 - 10/2016

WordPress plugin that adds a Converge payment gateway to WooCommerce (an eCommerce solution for WordPress).

• Professional Engineering License Manager

www.pelicensemanager.com

Joomla, MySQL, PHP

08/2012 - Present

Membership based web application built on the Joomla content management system that helps engineers manage continuing education requirements for professional engineering licenses.

 ComputerSMS Android and Desktop Applications Android, Java jacobmdavidson.com/computersms/

10/2015

Send and receive SMS text messages through an Android phone using a desktop application connected to the same local area network. Includes multicast DNS to simplify service discovery, XML message passing, and AES-128 message encryption derived from a Diffie-Hellman key exchange.

 Surveying Coordinate Transformation C#.NET jacobmdavidson.com/coordinate-transformation/

08/2014

Created for the survey department of Patrick Engineering, Inc., this WPF application transforms survey coordinates from one coordinate system to another using the least squares methodology.

• SMorSe for Android

jacobmdavidson.com/smorse/

Android, Java

07/2014

Converts incoming SMS text messages to Morse code based on the ITU-R M.1667-1 recommendation, and plays or vibrates the message in accordance with the volume settings of the phone.